JUSTIN ADAMS

Burlington, VT 05401 (802) 922-6669 justin.adams@uvm.edu

PROFILE

Electrical Engineer with 3 years of project management experience in medium-sized business operations and experience acting as an international liaison to the Republic of Korea. Received a Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering with honors, continued to research trends in mathematics and computation through the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers' (IEEE). Currently studying Computer Science at the University of Vermont with a focus in Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, and Quantum Computing. Seeking a motivated research team to improve electrical design, computational skill, and quantitative reasoning.

EDUCATION

University of Vermont Burlington, VT

June 2018 - Present

- Developing a quantum-based operating system to improve computational performance and linear differential equation solvers
- Developed a NP Hard reduction of the three-color map graph theory problem using a Quantum Computer in Melbourne, Australia
- · Proved a faster algorithm, which eliminates pre-sorting, for calculating the minimum Euclidean distance

University of Vermont Burlington, VT

January 2011 – June 2014

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

- Recipient of the Irving Lisman Scholarship for superior academic performance from non-traditional students
- Recipient of the Reserve Service Member Scholarship for outstanding leadership, academic performance, and military decorum

ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING PROFICIENCIES

VLSI Digital Design Solid State Chemistry Simulation (Q-Chem) Qiskit Application Development MongoDB Data Analytics ASIC Production Processes
Analog Circuit Production Processes
Reactive and Fresnel SNR Analysis
KiCad
LTSpice (digital) / PSpice (analog)

LabView Systems Engineering FPGA Programming & Design Numerical Method Applications in CS Numerical Method Applications in EE Numerical Method Applications in QC

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

U.S. Army Fort Hood, TX Project Manager & International Liaison

October 2014 – June 2018 June 2017 – June 2018

- Managed projects and enforced safety standards for 500 personnel and the assets of a \$232,000,000 organization
- Served as the primary point of contact and planner for international operations in the organization
- Prepared publications to develop mutual understanding of corporate operations and inspire international collaboration
- Provided recommendations on employing the assets and personnel of a large-sized business valued more than \$3 billion to executive level management in accordance with international conventions and internal standard operating procedures

Operations Supervisor

November 2014 – June 2017

- Supervised forty employees; motivated, instructed, trained, and directed them in conduct of land warfare operations for 32 months
- Provided guidance, enforced safety standards, trained personnel on maintenance procedures, and maintained accountability of \$23,000,000 of U.S. military equipment over a three-year period

Aurora North Software Burlington, VT **Implementation Engineer**

June 2014 - October 2014

• Designed a program module that creates logic diagrams for technical documentation using session layer logic as an input and Microsoft Publisher as an output. The program saved two hours per logic diagram totaling 1000+ hours saved per year.

MEMBERSHIPS

Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) Habitat for Humanity Volunteer USO Volunteer June 2014 – Present

June 2014 – Present

June 2014 - Present

REFERENCES

JUSTIN CLAY ADAMS 714 Pecos Drive Temple, TX 76504 (802) 922-6669 jcadams1987@icloud.com

University of Vermont

Nick Hella Computer Scientist – Marvell Technology Group nhella@mail.smcvt.edu C: (802) 734-4140

United States Army

John D. Moris Lieutenant Colonel – Commander john.d.moris.mil@mail.mil W: (254) 288-0465 C: (254) 368-9868

Jason T. Shuff Major – Operations Officer Jason.t.shuff.mil@mail.mil C: (706) 763-9511

Zachary A. Cottam Captain – Commander Zachary.a.cottam.mil@mail.mil C: (503) 956-0356

Timothy C. Endicott Captain – Operations Assistant United States Army Timothy.c.endicott.mil@mail.mil C: (912) 677-0296

Aaron D. Ballard Captain – Operations Assistant Aaron.d.ballard.mil@mail.mil C: (214) 549-7748

Aurora North Software

Bob Fishel Implementation Engineer Bob.fishel@auroranorth.com W: (802) 540-2504